Finding Aid for Sherwin T. Wine papers, 1930s-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 34)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 35)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 36)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 37)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 38)
  - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 38)
  - Cassette: Staying Sane in a Crazy World, 2001 (Box 38)
  - Compact Discs: lectures and a memorial service, 3 optical disks in 1 folder CDs
    - (Lillian) Genser Memorial Service, 2006 (Box 38)
    - "Rabbi Wine at the Triangle Chapter of Humanistic Judaism", 2003 (Box 38)
    - "Return to Our Roots", 2003 (Box 38)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series contains photographs, videotapes, and publicity posters. The photographs are largely of Wine (from youth to adulthood and in professional as well as leisure activities) and Center for New Thinking events; the videotapes document Wine and others speaking on humanism and Humanistic Judaism; and the posters include one announcing Wine's retirement celebration at the Birmingham Temple. This series also includes a DVD of a oral history interview with Wine.
  - Photographs
    - Armenian Jewish Cemetery, 2003 (Box 39)
      (JPEG images on a CD-R)
    - Center for New Thinking (programs and events)
      (see also oversize album, 1999-2006, in Box 41)
      - 1980s-2000s, 2 folders (Box 39)
      - 1990s (Box 39)
    - Colorado Congregation for Humanistic Judaism hosts Sherwin T. Wine, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Picnic (JPEG images on a CD-R), 2005-2006 (Box 39)
    - Religious Ceremonies performed by Sherwin T. Wine, 1983-2005 (Box 39)
    - Russian Trip, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Secular Humanistic Judaism Conferences, 1990s (Box 39)
    - Wine, Sherwin T.
      (see also oversize folder)
      - Childhood and Adolescence, 1930s-1940s (Box 39)
      - Seminary, 1950s (Box 39)
      - Portraits and Miscellaneous
        - Undated (Box 39)
        - 1990s-2000s (Box 39)
  - DVD: "JFMD Oral History" (Rabbi Wine), 2005 (Box 39)
  - Videotapes (VHS)
    - Education for Shared Values in Pluralistic Societies, undated (Box 39)
    - Essays on Richard Rodriguez and Robert Pinsky, 1999 (Box 39)
    - Humanism and Human Relations, 1994 (Box 39)
    - Humanistic Judaism, undated (Box 39)
    - HumCon, 2001 (Box 40)
      (conference sponsored by the L.A. Freethought Federation)
    - Introduction to Humanistic Judaism, undated (Box 40)
    - Shared Values in a Pluralistic Society, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Two Lectures by Paul Mendes-Flohr, 2001 (Box 40)
  - Publicity Posters, undated; 2003 (Folder 1)
Related Material
As of 2009, additional information on Sherwin T. Wine and his associated organizations may be found on the Internet; available material includes the Birmingham Temple (http://www.birminghamtemple.org/), the Center for New Thinking (http://www.centerfornewthinking.com/), the International Institute for Secular Humanistic Judaism (http://www.iishj.org/), and the Society for Humanistic Judaism (http://www.shj.org/).